<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<portfolio>
  <item>
    <id>0</id>
    <title>Monty Hall Simulation</title>
    <date>2023</date>
    <imagelink>resources/gallery/monty.png</imagelink>
    <techniques>Probability simulation. Python: matplotlib, numpy.</techniques>
    <description>Created a simulation of the Monty Hall problem for an article I wrote on Medium. Most of the work honestly went into making
    the graph look nice. I wanted it to match the colour scheme of the other diagrams in the article. </description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>1</id>
    <title>CNN for digit recognition</title>
    <date>2022</date>
    <imagelink>resources/gallery/ml.gif</imagelink>
    <techniques>Python: pytorch, manim. Convolutional neural networks. </techniques>
    <description>I wanted to create a nice animated diagram of a CNN (convolutional neural network) for an article I wrote on Medium.
    The article was generally about artificial intelligence, and I thought it would be helpful to have a nice illustrative gif of a classic
    AI problem - recognising digits. I created this animation using Pytorch and Manim. If you look carefully, you'll notice how the input - 
    a hand-drawn digit, 7, feeds information forward through the layers of the neural network. The network correctly classifies the digit
    as a seven - although you'll notice it also very vaguely thinks it might be a 2, which makes sense.</description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <id>2</id>
    <title>Simulation of double pendulums</title>
    <date>2022</date>
    <imagelink>resources/gallery/pendulum.gif</imagelink>
    <techniques>Python: matplotlib, numpy. Mathematical modelling. ODEs. </techniques>
    <description>I created this for an article I wrote on Medium about beautiful mathematics for everyday life. I wanted to illustrate some
    chaotic behaviour - so I chose to create an animation of double pendulums. Double pendulums are fascinating, because they demonstrate chaos 
    so clearly. With just the slightest of differences in the starting momentums and angles of the two pendulums, their behaviour diverges
    incredibly quickly. So it is with many things in the world.</description>
  </item>
</portfolio> 